Guide to the Jay Haley Collection, 1957-2007 M1733
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3. Haley’s Work, 1953-2004
  - Subseries 3.4 Film and Audio Materials: film scripts, interview transcriptions, correspondence, grant proposals, agreements, 1953 - 2000
    - Enacted Cases. Misc. Excerpts from Interviews; M Family, Mother's Day Card; Paul Riley: A Delinquent Family, (scripts), 1953 - 1956 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Headshrinker - Television Series, (description); Episode: The Lady was a Gentleman, with Don D. Jackson, (pilot script, mimeographed typescript), 1962 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - The Small Monster. TV Series: The Eleventh Hour, (typescript), 1960s (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Milton H. Erickson Hypnotic Demonstration, (letter, abstract, and transcript), 1964 - 1991 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Only on Sunday, (film script), 1972 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Coming Home from the Hospital, (film script, audio cue sheet, letter, and annotated typescript of chapter III), 1981 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Children Who Fall Out, (film script) (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Enacted Cases: Unbalancing a Couple; Approaching a Crisis; The Guaranteed Cure, (scripts), 1998 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Leaving Home, (film script), 1980 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - The Bossy Daughter, (typescript of transcript) (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Jay Haley and Don Jackson. Theoretical Dialogue, (transcript), 1956 - 1957 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - It Depends Upon Your Theory of Therapy!? Sandra E. Neil interviews Haley, (transcript); Networker Interview, (annotated transcript), 1985-1987 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Interview with Jay Haley, Martinez CA., (annotated transcript), 1989 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Jay Haley interviews Kay Thompson, (transcript), 1991 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - An Interview with Jay Haley by Mony Elkaïm, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Edited Telephone Consultations with Jay Haley: George Stone, Scott Ward, Sarah French, 1995; 1997 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Conversation with Jay Haley About Teaching and Learning Therapy, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Jay Haley Interview with Wendel A. Ray, Kristen Lee, Marty Carroll, and David Govener, (transcript), 1998 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Jay Haley Interview with Jon Carlson, (annotated transcript), 2000 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Jay Haley Interview with Anthony Yeo, (annotated transcripts) (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Jay Haley and Salvador Minuchin, Conversations 1-4, (annotated transcript) (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Jay Haley and Salvador Minuchin, Conversations 1-4, (transcript) (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Misc. Film and Audio Materials - Keeping Madness at Home, (cue sheet); Fragments of various unidentified film scripts; Project for Problem Young People, (grant proposal); Film Exhibition Agreement, (form and guidelines), 1970 - 1999 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3.5 Data on Therapists, Trainees, and Programs: questionnaires, statistics
    - Statistics of Various Studies, (handwritten and typed tables), - 1985 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Therapists Characteristics Overview, (filled out forms); Family Therapy Certification, (NACFT information and application booklet) (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3.6 Haley's Bibliographies, 1947-1998
    - Bibliography of Family Therapy 1947-1998, (typescript); Communication: Research and Therapy. Selected Papers of Jay Haley; Reprints; Publications; Books, (typescripts and computer printout) (Box 36, Folder 3)
- Series 4. Haley's Legal, Personal Documents, and Photographs, 1966-2007
  Of particular interest in this series are the awards, tributes and Festschriften for they offer an overview of Haley’s impact on the field of Psychotherapy.
  - Subseries 4.1 Contracts, Accreditations, Agreements, Releases, Copyright, 1966-1999
    - Releases: On Haley's and Hoffman's book on family psychotherapy, 1966, (letters); Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic. Video releases, 1972, (memo); Philadelphia Child Guidance Clinic. Legal Clearance of Material for Publication, 1974, (signed forms); Filming authorization forms for the Family Therapy Center., 1966-1974 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Copyright. On "Interminable Therapy" published in the Networker, (letters and forms); Copyright Clearance Center, Academic Permission Service, 1995, (agreement guidelines, letters, and forms); Spanish Translation Rights for Conversations on Therapy, (letter and memorandum agreement), 1990-1995 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - American Counseling Association Liability Insurance, Policy holder information (publications, forms, and letters), 1990-1996 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - American Association for Marriage and Family Therapy Accreditation, (letter and accreditation standards form), 1995 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4.2 Personal Documents: diplomas, school transcripts, CV, 1941-1952
    - Sacramento Junior College Diploma for Fred S. Haley, 1940; Sacramento High School Diploma, 1941; University of California Los Angeles, Transcripts, 1943; Stanford University, Transcript, 1952., 1940-1952 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4.3 Haley's Collection of Quotes
    - Quotes by Haley and Others, (typed on cards) (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 4.4 Awards, Certifications, Tributes, Festschriften, 1975-2007
    - Special Tribute to Jay Haley by The Milton H. Erickson Foundation, (letters, publications, typescript of acceptance speech, and photo of gift), 1999-2000 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Tribute to Jay Haley, Phoenix, AZ, (typescript of acceptance speech), 1999 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Misc. Awards and Certifications: XV Congreso Médico Centroamericano, 1973; Honorary Member, Colegio de Médicos y Cirujanos, Costa Rica, 1975; In appreciation, plaque, Atlanta Institute for family Studies, 1981; Distinguished Achievement Award, American Family Therapy Association, 1981; Lifetime Achievement Award, The Milton H. Erickson Foundation, 1983; The Milton H. Erickson Foundation, Founding Editorial Board Member. The Ericksonian Monographs, 1984; Certificate of Approval for a Drug Abuse Treatment and Rehabilitation Program, 1987; Distinguished Professional Contribution for Family Therapy Award, American Association for Marriage and Family Therapy, 1990; Distinguished Membership Award. International Association of Marriage and Family Counselors, 1990; The American Association for Marriage and Family Therapy Supervision Committee, 1993 and1998; The American Association for Marriage and Family Therapy, 1999; International Association of Marriage and Family Counselors, 2000-2001; American Association for Marriage and Family Therapy, Outstanding Family Therapist in California, 2001; Doctor of Humane Letters, Alliant International University, 2002; The National Credentialing Academy for Certified Family Therapists, Inc.; The American Society of Clinical Hypnosis: Honorary Fellow, n.d.; The International Society of Hypnosis: The Jay Haley Early Career Award for Innovative Contributions to Hypnosis, 2009, 1975-2009 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Honorary Doctorate, Alliant International University, (publication, congratulatory cards, typescript of acceptance speech), 2002 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Festschrift: Jay Haley on Jay Haley with Michael D. Yapko, (typescript), 2007 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Obituaries, (letters, journal articles, newspaper clippings), 2007 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 4.5 Photographs, 1950-1960
    - William Fry, John Weakland, Gregory Bateson, and Jay Haley, ca. 1960 (Box 36, Folder 16)
- Series 5. Milton H. Erickson M.D., 1932-2010
  This series offers an overview of Haley’s life-long involvement with and study on Milton H. Erickson.
  - Subseries 5.1 Erickson's Writings, 1932-1974
    - The Experimental Demonstration of Unconscious Mentation by Automatic Writing, 1932, (typescript); A Brief Survey of Hypnotism, 1934, (typescript, fragment); A Study of Experimental Neurosis Hypnotically Induced in a Case of Ejaculatio Praecox, 1935, (typescript and a later reprint); Note on a Word Association Test, 1936, (typescript); Development of Apparent Unconsciousness During Hypnotic Reliving of a Traumatic Experience, 1937, (typescript); The Application of Hypnosis to Psychiatry, 1939, (typescript); An Experimental Investigation of the Possible Anti-Social Use of Hypnosis, 1939, (typescript); Experimentally Elicited Salivary and Related Responses to Hypnotic Visual Hallucinations Confirmed by Personality Reactions, 1943, (typescript); The Development of Aphasia-Like Reactions From Hypnotically Induced Amnesia, 1943, (typescript); Psychoanalytic Implications in Hypnosis – Unconscious Mental Activity, 1944, (typescripts); Hypnosis in Medicine, 1944, (typescript);Treatment of a Case of Hysterical Urinary Retention, 1944, (typescript); Selma Carr, 1944, (typescript); Janet Carr, n.d., (typescript); My Life, by Ruth Bye, n.d. (typescript), 1932-1944 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Concerning Present Inadequacies in the Legal Recognition and Handling of the Mentally Ill, 1946, (reprint); Hypnotic Psychotherapy, 1948, (typescript); Hypnotherapy of Two Psychosomatic Dental Problems, 1952, (typescript); Therapy of a Psychosomatic Headache, 1953, (typescript); Special Techniques of Brief Hypnotherapy, 1954, (typescript); The Development of an Acute Limited Obsessional Hysterical State in a Normal Hypnotic Subject, 1954, (typescript); Further Considerations of Time Distortion: Subjective Time Condensation, Time Expansion and Their Therapeutic Applications, 1958, (annotated typescripts); Naturalistic Techniques of Hypnosis, 1958, (typescripts); The Basis of Hypnosis, 1959, (typescript); Pantomime Techniques in Hypnosis and the Implications, circa 1959, (typescript); The Utilization of Patient Behavior in the Hypnotherapy of Obesity: Three Case Reports, 1960, (typescripts); Psychogenic Alteration of Menstrual Functioning: Three Instances, 1960, (typescript); An Investigation of Optokinetic Nystagmus, 1962, (typescript); Hypnotically Oriented Psychotherapy in Organic Disease, 1964, (typescript), 1946-1964 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Deep Hypnosis and its Induction, (typescript), 1952 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Advanced Techniques of Hypnosis and Therapy. Selected Papers of Milton H. Erickson, M.D. Edited by Jay Haley, (annotated typescript), 1967 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - A Field Investigation by Hypnosis of Sound Loci Importance in Human Behavior, 1973, (reprint); Varieties of Hypnotic Amnesia, 1974, (reprint), 1973-1974 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Therapeutic Self-Exploration in the Hypnotic State, (typescript); A Brief Note on the Origins of the Hand-Levitation Technique, (typescript); Deepening of Trance; The Phenomena of Hypnotism, (typescript); General Principals of Induction and Utilization, (typescript); Indirect Techniques, (typescript); The Clinical and Therapeutic Applications of Time Distortion, (annotated reprint); Possible Detrimental Effects of Experimental Hypnosis, (annotated reprint); miscellaneous fragments (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Reprints, 1934-1958 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Reprints, 1959-1964 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Reprints, 1965-1967 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 5.2 Erickson's Cases
    - Identified Cases: Restricted, 1944- (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified Cases: An instance of Aggression Transformation, (typescript and letter); Breast Development Possibly Influenced by Hypnosis: Two Instances and the Psychotherapeutic Results (typescript); Man Reading Problem, (typescript); The Bowel Movement Girl, (typescript); The Nursing Husband, (typescript); The New Married Nurses with Perverse Husband, (typescript); Patient D, (typescript); Mary, (typescript); misc. notes and fragments (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 5.3 Transcripts of Conversations with Erickson, 1955-1963
    - Tape Recordings’ Lists and Outlines, (typescript), 1955-1971 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Erickson Brief Therapy Conference, (typescript), 1956 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Haley interviews Milton Erickson, (typescript fragments), 1956 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Haley interviews Elizabeth Erickson, (typescript), 1956 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Haley interviews Milton Erickson about his life, (typescript), 1957 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Haley, Bateson, and Weakland interview Milton Erickson, (typescript), 1958 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Erickson Philadelphia Conference I, (typescript), 1958 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Erickson Philadelphia Conference II. Interview with Erickson, Gorton, Weizenhofer, Farnham, Haley, and an unknown voice, (typescript), 1958 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Erickson Philadelphia Conference III. Interview with Erickson, Gorton, Weizenhofer, Farnham, Haley, and an unknown voice, (typescript), 1958 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Erickson Philadelphia Conference IV. Interview with Erickson, Gorton, Weizenhofer, Farnham, Haley, and an unknown voice, (typescript), 1958 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Erickson Philadelphia Conference V. Interview with Erickson, Gorton, Weizenhofer, Farnham, Haley, and an unknown voice, (typescript), 1958 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Erickson Philadelphia Conference VI. Interview with Erickson, Gorton, Weizenhofer, Farnham, Haley, and an unknown voice, (typescript), 1958 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Erickson Philadelphia Conference VII. Interview with Erickson, Gorton, Weizenhofer, Farnham, Haley, and an unknown voice, (typescript), 1958 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Hypnotic Demonstration: Ruth’s Induction with Commentary, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Selecting a Subject and Technique, (annotated typescript), 1959 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Haley interviews Milton Erickson, (annotated typescript), 1959 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Erickson Psychotherapy Conference I, (annotated typescript), 1959 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Erickson Psychotherapy Conference II, (annotated typescript), 1959 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Erickson Psychotherapy Conference III, (annotated typescript), 1959 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Erickson’s Second Conference, (annotated typescript), 1959 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Haley and Weakland interview Milton Erickson, (annotated typescript), 1961 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Erickson Interviews. Transcriptions of Tapes 1 - 4, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Erickson Interviews. Transcriptions of Tapes 4 - 6, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Misc. Interview Transcripts Fragments (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 5.4 Correspondence, 1955-1971
    - Gregory Bateson; Dezso Levendula, 1955-1965 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Jay Haley, 1956-1971 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 5.5 Miscellaneous
    - Erickson’s Bibliographies (includes a letter from Elizabeth Erickson), 1965-2010 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - On Erickson and His Work, 1985-2004 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - III European Congress on Ericksonian Hypnosis and Psychotherapy, Venice Italy, 1998; Photograph of Erickson; The Milton Erickson Foundation Newsletter 1999; Articles by Ernest L. Rossi and John O. Beahrs; Fragments, 1998-1999 (Box 42, Folder 5)
- Series 6. Other Author’s Writings, 1946-2007
  This series consists of the writings, mainly of colleagues, that Haley collected throughout his life.
  - Subseries 6.1 On Jay Haley: His Work and Philosophy; Reviews of his Books, Articles, and Films, 1977-2007
    - Jay Haley’s Approach to Family Therapy. A Professional Paper Submitted in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirements for the Degree Masters of Science: Marriage, Family, Child Counseling, by Katherine W. Keith, 1982, (typescript); Jay Haley: Mad Genius. Family Oriented Treatment, John J. McCarthy, 1986, (typescript); Another View on “Madness” by Loren R. Mosher, Family Forum News 1988, (newsletter issue); On Jay Haley. Letters to the Editor. Family Forum News 1988, (newsletter issue); Approaches to Madness Shared by Cross-Cultural Healing Systems and Strategic Family Therapy, by Madeleine Richeport-Haley, 1998, (reprint); Haley's Conversation with Jon Carlson, 2002, (e-mail and typescript), 1982-2002 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Changing Directives: The Strategic Therapy of Jay Haley, Jeffrey K. Zeig, ed., (book), 2001 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Reviews of Haley’s Books I, 1977-1999 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of Haley’s Books II, 2005 - 2007 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 6.2 On and By Gregory Bateson, 1946-1992
    - "Physical thinking and Social Problems," 1946 (reprint); "Structure and Process in Social Relations," with Jurgen Ruesch, 1949, (reprint); "Metalogue: About Games and Being Serious," 1951, (reprint); "Metalogue: Why Do things Have Outlines, 1951, (reprint); Metalogues: Why do Frenchmen?" 1951, (reprint); "Applied Metalinguistics and International Relations," 1951, (reprint); "For God’s Sake, Margaret. Conversation with Gregory Bateson and Margaret Mead," 1976, (photocopies of journal); The Life of Gregory Bateson, by David Lipset, 1977, (typescript of one chapter); A Matter of Character by the Ghost of Gregory Bateson, 1992, (typescript); "Cultural and Thematic Analysis of Fictional Films," n.d. (reprint), 1946-1992 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 6.3 Don Jackson, John H. Weakland, and the History of the Palo Alto Group, 1954-1987
    - "Some Factors Influencing the Oedipus Complex," by Don Jackson, 1954, (reprint); "A Note on the Importance of Trauma in the Genesis of Schizophrenia," by Don Jackson, 1957, (reprint); "Patient and Therapist Observations on the Circumstances of a Schizophrenic Episode," by John Weakland and Don Jackson, 1958, (reprint); "Conjoint Family Therapy," by Don Jackson, 1965, (reprint); History of the Palo Alto Group, 1987, by Carl Broderick, (typescript), 1954-1987; On History of the Palo Alto Group, 1987, by Carl Broderick, see also Haley's "Development of a Theory," in box 10, folder 20 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 6.4. Madeleine Richeport-Haley, 1992-1998
    - "The Interface Between Multiple Personality, Spirit Mediumship, and Hypnosis," 1992, (reprint); "Ethnicity in Family Therapy: A Comparison of Brief Strategic Therapy and Culture-Focused Therapy," 1998, (reprint), 1992-1998 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 6.5 George Stone and Barbara Peeks, 1984-1987
    - Misc. Student Papers, 1984-1987 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 6.6 Strategic Therapy, 1968-1998
    - Stages of Strategic Therapy, by Judith Mazza, n.d. (typescript); "Fulfillment of Therapeutic Tasks as a Precondition for Acceptance in Therapy," by Haim Omer, 1985, (reprint); "Strategic Marital Therapy for Depression," by James C. Coyne, 1986, (photocopies of a book); The Significance of the Interview in Strategic Marital Therapy, by James C. Coyne, n.d., (typescript); The Gandhi Technique, by Neil P. Schiff and Richard Belson, n.d., (typescript), 1968-1998 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6.7 Schizophrenia, Drug Treatment, and Brain Studies, 1964-1996
    - Study of Interaction in Families of Schizophrenic Patients, by Elliot G. Mishler, (forms, notes of studies, and letter), 1964 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Analysis of Family Sessions and Family Tasks, Salvador Minuchin, (typescripts and letter); Characteristics of Interaction Patterns in Families with a Schizophrenic Child, by Henry L. Lennard, Maurice R. Beaulieu, and Nolen G. Embrey, (typescript), 1964 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Writings on Schizophrenia I, 1967-1988 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Writings on Schizophrenia II, 1989-1996 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Writings on Schizophrenia III (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 6.8 On Family Therapy, 1970-1990
    - The Case History Method in the Study of Family Process. A Report of the Committee on the Family of the Group for the Advancement of Psychiatry, (typescript), 1970 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - The Book of Therapy and The Book of Family Therapy, two book reviews by O. Spurgeon English, 1972, (typescripts); "Confidentiality and Privileged Communications: Legal Dilemma for Family Therapists," 1989, (reprint); "An Investigation of Systemic Conceptualizations of Parent-Child Coalitions and Symptom Change," by Barton J. Mann, Charles M. Borduin, Scott W. Henggeler, and David M. Blaske, (reprint), 1972- 1990 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 6.9 Misc. Topics on Psychotherapy: Articles, Newsletters, Publications, 1896-2001
    - On Psychotherapy I, 1896-2001 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - On Psychotherapy II (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 6.10 Fiction and Other Writings, 1957-1961
    - Stories by Carl Armandola: Time in Kingman; Doing Time. Others Have Been Known to Take up Woodcarving or Painting. My Racket is Words; Divertimenti. Written for Mr. Jay Haley, Roshi and Friend, (Typescripts and letters), 1961- (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Writings by Lewis Ellingham: Notes on Spanish Religious Architecture, 1957, (typescript); A Year in the Life of an Innocent Young Man, 1958, (typescript); Nauphlion, 1959, (typescript), 1957-1959 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Le Roman de ma Vie. Play in Three Acts. Author unknown. (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Piéce de Nausicaa. Play in Six Tableux. Author unknown (Box 45, Folder 8)
- Series 7. Family Process Journals, Jay Haley ed., 1962-1988
  This series documents Haley’s role as editor of the Family Process journal.
  - Subseries 7.1 Family Process Journals: 1962 Vol. 1 Nr. 2; 1963 Vol. 2 Nr. 1; 1963 Vol. 2 Nr. 2; 1964 Vol. 3 Nr. 2; 1965 Vol. 4 Nr. 1; 1965 Vol. 4 Nr. 2; 1966 Vol. 5 Nr. 1; 1967 Vol. 6 Nr. 1; 1967 Vol. 6 Nr. 2; 1968 Vol. 7 Nr. 1; 1968 Vol. 7 Nr. 2; 1969 Vol. 8 Nr. 1; 1969 Vol. 8 Nr. 2; 1970 Vol. 9 Nr. 1; 1988 Vol. 27 Nr. 4, 1962-1988 (Box 46)
- Series 8. Media, 1969-2004
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
  Non-digital audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. For additional information see Stanford University, Special Collections and University Archives, Duplication Services.
  As mentioned in Series 3 Haley pioneered the recording of therapy sessions, and created many training films. This series documents his extensive production of training films.
  - Subseries 8.1 Audio: Reel to Reel and Cassette Tapes
    - Don D. Jackson, M. D. Memorial Conference, Asilomar California, Feb. 27 - March 2, 1969. Organized by Jay Haley: Opening Address, Dr. Ackermann; Sessions 1 – 7: Panel and General Discussions, (8 reel to reel tapes, 1/4" tape, 3-3/4 IPS; typescript with an introduction to the conference and list of participants); Milton H. Erickson: Multiple Personality, (60 min. audio cassette), See also Haley's essay on the Don D. Jackson Memorial Conference: series 3.2 box 28 folder 7 (Box 53)
  - Subseries 8.2 Audio: Compact Discs
    - Milton H. Erickson M.D. In His Own Voice. 1) Problem Drinkers; 2) Sex Therapy, the Male; 3) Sex Therapy, the Female; 4) Multiple Personality (see 8.1 audio cassettes). Editor and narrator: Jay Haley. Co-Editor M. Richeport-Haley (Box 55)
  - Subseries 8.3 Video Cassettes, 1995-2001
    - Produced by Jay Haley and Madeleine Richeport-Haley: Dance and Trance of Balinese Children, 1995; Unbalancing a Couple, 1998; Jay Haley Seminar on Clinical Hypnosis, 1998; Changing a Violent Family, 2000; A Positive Approach with a Psychotic Couple, 2000; The Boy who Can’t Stop Fighting, 2001, 1995-2001 (Box 54)
  - Subseries 8.4 Digital Video Discs, 1978-2004